# Joonwon Choi

Formal Verification Engineer at Apple One Apple Park Way, Cupertino, CA 95014 +1-339-225-5940 | joonwonc@apple.com | http://joonwon.net/c

# Current Position

## Formal Verification Engineer, Apple

03/15/2021 -Current

I have worked on formally verifying memory subsystems in various Apple products. Reasoning about memory subsystems is challenging due to its complex mechanism to allow concurrent executions of memory requests. Our team employs formalmethods tools to provide a mathematical guarantee that the systems are safe. Particularly, I have achieved verifying several memory components so we have better confidence in the safety of those components.

# Education

## Massachusetts Institute of Technology

09/01/2016 -02/17/2021

Doctor of Philosophy in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

- Graduate Cumulative GPA: 5.0 (on a 5.0 scale)

#### Massachusetts Institute of Technology

09/01/2014 -06/03/2016

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

- Graduate Cumulative GPA: 5.0 (on a 5.0 scale)

#### Seoul National University

03/01/2006 -02/26/2013

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering Double major in Mathematical Sciences

- Graduated with honors (summa cum laude)

# **Publications**

- [1] Kami: A Platform for High-Level Parametric Hardware Specification and its Modular Verification. paper Joonwon Choi, Muralidaran Vijayaraghavan, Benjamin Sherman, Adam Chlipala, Arvind. Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN International Conference on Functional Programming (ICFP'17). September 2017.
- [2] Structural Design and Proof of Hierarchical Cache-Coherence Protocols. thesis

#### Ioonwon Choi

Ph.D. Thesis in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Thesis Supervisor: Adam Chlipala and Arvind

[3] An Inlining Approach to Formal Hardware Semantics. thesis

### Joonwon Choi

M.S. Thesis in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Thesis Supervisor: Arvind

- [4] Integration Verification Across Software and Hardware for a Simple Embedded System. paper Andres Erbsen, Samuel Gruetter, Joonwon Choi, Clark Wood, Adam Chlipala. Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI'21).
- [5] EverCrypt: A Fast, Verified, Cross-Platform Cryptographic Provider. paper Jonathan Protzenko, Bryan Parno, Aymeric Fromherz, Chris Hawblitzel, Marina Polubelova, Karthikeyan Bhargavan,

Benjamin Beurdouche, **Joonwon Choi**, Antoine Delignat-Lavaud, Cédric Fournet, Natalia Kulatova, Tahina Ramananandro, Aseem Rastogi, Nikhil Swamy, Christoph M. Wintersteiger, and Santiago Zanella-Beguelin. IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (SP'20). May 2020.

[6] Crellvm: Verified Credible Compilation for LLVM. <a href="paper">paper</a>
Jeehoon Kang, Yoonseung Kim, Youngju Song, Juneyoung Lee, Sanghoon Park, Mark Dongyeon Shin, Yonghyun Kim, Sungkeun Cho, Joonwon Choi, Chung-Kil Hur, and Kwangkeun Yi.
Proceedings of the ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI'18).
June 2018.

# Honors & Awards

Microsoft Research Cambridge, United Kingdom

Software Engineering Intern (SWE Intern)

Software Engineer (Skilled Industry Personnel as alternative military service)

Research Intern

Google, Korea

allm Games, Korea

Kwanjeong Educational Fellowship	Sep 2014 – May 2019
MIT Emerson Scholarship for Private Music Study	Sep 2014 – May 2018
Top Honor (summa cum laude) Certification Seoul National University	Feb 2013
Presidential Science Scholarship	Mar 2006 – Feb 2013
Teaching Experience	
MIT 6.887: Formal Reasoning About Programs Teaching Assistant	Spring 2017
SNU 4190.310: Programming Languages Teaching Assistent	Fall 2013
Working Experience	
Apple, United States Formal Verification Engineer	03/15/2021 - Current

Last updated: January 10, 2022 http://joonwon.net/c/docs/cv.pdf 07/02/2018 -09/21/2018

04/13/2009 -09/12/2011

01/05/2009 -04/03/2009